The Celluloid Closet is a documentary, history film directed by Rob Epstein.
Exuberant, eye-opening movie that serves up a dazzling hundred-year history of
the role of gay men and lesbians have had on the silver screen.
Film contains fabulous footage from 120 films showing the changing face of cinema sexuality,
from cruel stereotypes to covert love to the activist triumphs of the 1990s.
Narrator (voice), played by Lily Tomlin.
Self, played by Tony Curtis.
Self, played by Susan Sarandon.
Self, played by Gore Vidal.
Self, played by Whoopi Goldberg.
Self, played by Antonio Fargas.
The Celluloid Closet is a 1996 American documentary film directed and co-written by Rob
Epstein and Jeffrey Friedman, and executive produced by Howard Rosenman.
The film is based on Vito Russo's 1981 book The Celluloid Closet: Homosexuality in the
Movies, and on lecture and film clip presentations he gave from 1972 to 1982.
Russo had researched the history of how motion pictures, especially Hollywood films,
had portrayed gay, lesbian, bisexual, and transgender characters.
The Celluloid Closet was given a limited release in select theatres, including the Castro Theatre in San
Francisco in April 1996, and then shown on cable channel HBO as part of its series America Undercover.
The film explores themes of media, hollywood, lgbt.